<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Merlijn Van Holder</title>
    <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Merlijn Van Holder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://merlijnvanholder.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to bring my website back for a while, especially as I&amp;rsquo;ve become less active on social media. In an era of endless feeds and brain rot, returning to a personal website and blog feels right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annual web hosting bill added up, so I eventually cancelled it. I used to run WordPress, which does offer a nice back-end for managing content. But needing PHP, a MySQL database, and frequent updates to keep things secure always felt too heavy for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare #30 – Tribe of the Giant</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/ludum-dare-30-tribe-of-the-giant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/ludum-dare-30-tribe-of-the-giant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ludum Dare is a fantastic challenge: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ludumdare.com/&#34;&gt;make a game from scratch in 48 hours&lt;/a&gt;. Every year more people join, resulting in thousands of entries by the end of the weekend. This was my second time participating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running into time-wasting problems is dangerous when you only have two days. Preparing before you start is key. While there&amp;rsquo;s some value in learning new software under pressure, it&amp;rsquo;s better to use tools you already know: the C# programming language, Blender, and Unity in my case. Prepare your work environment before the weekend starts. I set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/archive/p/chronolapse/&#34;&gt;Chronolapse&lt;/a&gt; to capture &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PuTk-GsvBXs&#34;&gt;a timelapse&lt;/a&gt; and OBS for livestreaming on Twitch. Avoid nasty surprises once you start, nothing derails a jam like broken software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#Nar8 2014 – Compute Thought</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/nar8-2014-compute-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/nar8-2014-compute-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compute Thought is a short cyberpunk point-and-click adventure game created for #Nar8, a narrative‑focused game jam. I usually lean toward gameplay and level design rather than writing, so this project was a deliberate exercise in story building. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://merlijnvh.itch.io/compute-thought&#34;&gt;play it on itch.io&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MerlijnVH/Compute-Thought&#34;&gt;browse the source code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Prototype&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/nar8-2014-compute-thought/media/nar8-2014-compute-thought-01.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The opening scene is my favourite, but went through many iterations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game centers on a detective investigating the murder, in a world where humans and androids coexist (uneasily). Classic cyberpunk stories like Blade Runner and Ghost in the Shell inspired me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare #29 – Ocean Rescue</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/ludum-dare-29-ocean-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/ludum-dare-29-ocean-rescue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ludum Dare #29 ran from April 25th – 27th, a 48-hour jam where anyone builds a game around a single theme. Unlike the Global Game Jam, it&amp;rsquo;s common to work solo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the theme &amp;ldquo;Beneath the Surface&amp;rdquo;, I set out to make a game about a giant monster lurking in the depths, part sandworm from Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dune&amp;rdquo;, part Moby-Dick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with a seafaring concept: you sail around collecting capsules drifting on the water. Other boats attack you, while the monster tries to swallow you whole. The game takes place at night, this covers up any art assets that look too rough around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tactical RPG Prototype</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/tactical-rpg-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/tactical-rpg-prototype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a few days prototyping a turn-based tactical RPG, a genre I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to love. &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/7650/XCOM_Terror_From_the_Deep/&#34;&gt;X-COM: Terror from the Deep&lt;/a&gt; hooked me when I was a kid, and only later did I truly come to appreciate it. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see the genre making a comeback with titles like &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/237990/The_Banner_Saga/&#34;&gt;The Banner Saga&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/200510/XCOM_Enemy_Unknown/&#34;&gt;X-COM: Enemy Unknown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a proper tactical game, players choose their actions turn-by-turn: moving, attacking, or guarding. During the computer&amp;rsquo;s turn, the AI identifies the nearest player character and moves in to attack. The battle ends when one side is defeated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Legion: Buckets of Blood Steam Release</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/foreign-legion-buckets-of-blood-steam-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/foreign-legion-buckets-of-blood-steam-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After six intense months of development, the game I&amp;rsquo;ve been pouring my energy into has finally been &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/36000/Foreign_Legion_Buckets_of_Blood/&#34;&gt;released on Steam&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreign Legion: Buckets of Blood is a fast-paced, stylized third‑person shooter. Missions range from defending an oil pipeline against waves of attackers to escorting a bus packed with tourists through hostile territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Oil Pipeline Mission&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/foreign-legion-buckets-of-blood-steam-release/media/foreign-legion-screenshot-01.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I created most of the levels and 3D environment art.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Tourist Bus Mission&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://merlijnvanholder.com/posts/foreign-legion-buckets-of-blood-steam-release/media/foreign-legion-screenshot-02.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The dawn escort mission is one of the prettier levels I built.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read Me</title>
      <link>https://merlijnvanholder.com/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merlijnvanholder.com/readme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Merlijn — a Belgian game developer and programmer who plays a lot of video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I split my time between three companies I founded: Mithra Games, my one-person indie studio; &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandafish.be/&#34;&gt;Pandafish&lt;/a&gt;, a web development studio; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mybeats.eu/&#34;&gt;MyB&amp;rsquo;eats&lt;/a&gt;, an app and loyalty platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with games since elementary school, building levels for Doom, Quake, Half-Life, and many more. Later, as a technical artist in the games industry. All in all I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on games for web, mobile, desktop and VR. These days I&amp;rsquo;m just doing my own thing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://godotengine.org/&#34;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
